<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Living Sports Analytics</title>
    <link>https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app</link>
    <description>Latest sports analytics research papers, blog posts, and grey literature — curated and classified by AI</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:11:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <image>
      <url>https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app/icon.png</url>
      <title>Living Sports Analytics</title>
      <link>https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>040 Injuries are negatively associated with team performance in professional cricket</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2021-ioc.38</link>
      <description>A retrospective analysis of 18 First-Class County Cricket teams over 9 seasons found a moderate negative correlation between injury burden and team performance (r = -0.36), with reductions in match injury burden of 74 days per 1,000 days of play associated with +13 County Championship points.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3004160027</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Living Sports Analytics</source>
      <category>cricket</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The associations between adolescents’ sports club participation and dietary habits</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tsm2.249</link>
      <description>A cross-sectional study of 1,917 adolescents aged 14-16 found that sports club participants reported healthier dietary habits (breakfast, vegetables, milk consumption) than non-participants, though both groups had inadequate fruit and vegetable intake.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3152616212</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Translational Sports Medicine</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>nutrition_recovery</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomechanical Symmetry during Drop Jump Landing and Takeoff in Adolescent Athletes Following Recent Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/sym13040639</link>
      <description>A 3D biomechanical analysis of 33 adolescent athletes (16 female) post-ACL reconstruction revealed persistent lower extremity asymmetries in landing and takeoff phases during vertical drop jumps, indicating the need for rehabilitation addressing both phases.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3153949823</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Symmetry</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of an Injury Prevention Program on Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury Risk Factors in Adolescent Females at Different Stages of Maturation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52082/jssm.2021.365</link>
      <description>A randomized controlled trial of 178 female basketball players across three maturation stages found that a 6-month injury prevention program limited high-risk movement patterns in early puberty and improved knee mechanics in post-pubertal athletes.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3154976275</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Journal of Sports Science and Medicine</source>
      <category>basketball</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence and Burden of Physical Problems in Female College Basketball Athletes: A 135-Day Prospective Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2147/oajsm.s300493</link>
      <description>A 135-day prospective cohort study of female college basketball athletes documented the prevalence and burden of common injuries including ankle sprains, ACL injuries, knee pain, and low-back pain.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3157148381</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Open Access Journal of Sports Medicine</source>
      <category>basketball</category>
      <category>epidemiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frequency and Characteristics of Injuries and Rehabilitation Procedures in Rugby Players in Poland and France</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18094835</link>
      <description>A survey of 60 professional rugby players from Poland and France found higher injury incidence in Poland but different injury types and rehabilitation approaches between countries, with sprain as the most common injury.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3158201357</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</source>
      <category>rugby</category>
      <category>epidemiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 2D video‐analysis scoring system of 90° change of direction technique identifies football players with high knee abduction moment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-021-06571-2</link>
      <description>A study of 34 competitive soccer players (18 male, 16 female) developed a 2D video-analysis scoring system for 90° change of direction technique that reliably identified players with elevated knee abduction moment, an ACL injury risk factor.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3159691252</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Knee Surgery Sports Traumatology Arthroscopy</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Profil Kondisi Fisik dan Motif Berprestasi Pada Siswa Ekstrakurikuler Sepakbola</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20884/1.paju.2021.2.2.3798</link>
      <description>A descriptive qualitative study of 25 high school soccer players found that physical conditioning was at a medium level while achievement motivation was high (80% rated as good), indicating the need for improved conditioning training.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3160374955</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Physical Activity Journal</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Personality Traits Influencing the Performance of Men in Team Sports in Terms of the Big Five</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.679724</link>
      <description>A study of 300 Polish team sport athletes using the NEO Five-Factor Inventory found that champions exhibited lower neuroticism, higher extraversion, and greater openness than non-champions, with personality trait distributions varying by sport.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3164883064</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Frontiers in Psychology</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>psychology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Peculiarities of Heart Rate Variability in Student Athletes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21103/article11(2)_oa9</link>
      <description>Athletics students showed significantly better heart rate variability and cardiac adaptive capacity compared to floorball players, indicating sport-specific physiological adaptations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3166681047</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Biomedicine</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>physiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I am going out!” – lifestyle sports and physical activity in adolescents</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-021-11066-3</link>
      <description>Participation in lifestyle sports (parkour, skateboarding) was significantly associated with higher moderate-to-vigorous physical activity levels in adolescents aged 10-15 years.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3166703229</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">BMC Public Health</source>
      <category>other</category>
      <category>player_development</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noncontact Knee Ligament Injury Prevention Screening in Netball: A Clinical Commentary with Clinical Practice Suggestions for Community-Level Players</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26603/001c.23553</link>
      <description>A clinical commentary on netball injury prevention reviewed theoretical frameworks, evidence types, and screening procedures to develop evidence-informed noncontact knee ligament injury prevention strategies for community-level female players.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3171201093</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy</source>
      <category>volleyball</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Motor Coordination Elicits Altered Lower Limb Biomechanics in Young Football (Soccer) Players: Implications for Injury Prevention through Wearable Sensors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/s21134371</link>
      <description>Young football players with poor motor coordination showed significantly altered hip and knee biomechanics (40% lower hip flexion, increased valgus) and limb asymmetries, indicating elevated ACL injury risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3174737737</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Sensors</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of a psychological and physiotherapeutic intervention on the occurrence of injuries (Efectos de una intervención psicológica y fisioterapeútica sobre la ocurrencia de lesiones)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12800/ccd.v16i48.1715</link>
      <description>Combined psychological intervention (motivation/anxiety) plus physiotherapy significantly reduced injury occurrence in male soccer players compared to physiotherapy alone or control at 6-month follow-up.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3176662015</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Cultura Ciencia y Deporte</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differences in strength and landing biomechanics between female jumpers and swimmers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3233/ies-210149</link>
      <description>Female long jumpers and high jumpers with 5 years of plyometric training showed greater leg strength but no improvement in landing biomechanics compared to swimmers, suggesting plyometrics alone may not reduce ACL injury risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3183022356</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Isokinetics and Exercise Science</source>
      <category>athletics</category>
      <category>biomechanics</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maturity alters drop vertical jump landing force‐time profiles but not performance outcomes in adolescent females</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.14025</link>
      <description>Maturity increased absolute landing and take-off forces in adolescent female athletes but did not improve relative force or spring-like behavior, with 65-80% displaying poor stretch-shortening cycle function across all maturational stages.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3183567693</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports</source>
      <category>athletics</category>
      <category>biomechanics</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analisis Indeks Massa Tubuh dan Kondisi Fisik Atlet Floorball Kota Surabaya</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26740/jossae.v6n2.p125-133</link>
      <description>Descriptive analysis of 20 male floorball athletes in Surabaya found deficient agility and speed (65% and 55% below standard), adequate endurance and power (55%), indicating need for targeted training program improvements.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3184336796</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">JOSSAE (Journal of Sport Science and Education)</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>physiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postural orientation, what to expect in youth athletes? A cohort study on data from the Malmö Youth Sport Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13102-021-00307-y</link>
      <description>Postural orientation errors improved from early to middle adolescence in youth athletes across team, individual, and aesthetic sports, with female athletes showing fewer errors than males at mid-adolescence.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3184350745</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">BMC Sports Science Medicine and Rehabilitation</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Randomised controlled trial comparing two group-based exercise programmes (team sport vs circuit training) on men’s health: study protocol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjsem-2021-001140</link>
      <description>Randomized controlled trial protocol comparing team sport and circuit training in 128 insufficiently active middle-aged men, measuring physical activity, quality of life, motivation, sleep, and metabolic health over 12 weeks.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3187730454</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">BMJ Open Sport &amp; Exercise Medicine</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing Normative Values for Inter-Limb Kinetic Symmetry During Landing in Uninjured Adolescent Athletes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26603/001c.25366</link>
      <description>Normative values for inter-limb kinetic symmetry during landing were established in 136 uninjured adolescent athletes, revealing that 55% of ACL-reconstructed athletes exhibited atypically high asymmetry.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3190439105</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commercialization processes within Swedish child and youth sport – a Deleuzioguttarian perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/17430437.2021.1944114</link>
      <description>High compliance with the Knee Control injury prevention program reduced injury prevalence by 35-60% in male youth floorball players but showed no effect in female players.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3194239045</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Sport in Society</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volleyball Fundamental Movement Learning Model in Primary School</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17309/tmfv.2021.3.02</link>
      <description>Game-centered volleyball learning model significantly improves fundamental movement outcomes in elementary school students compared to traditional instruction, with large effect sizes on skill acquisition.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3204267194</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Physical Education Theory and Methodology</source>
      <category>volleyball</category>
      <category>coaching</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is walking netball an effective, acceptable and feasible method to increase physical activity and improve health in middle- to older age women?: A RE-AIM evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-021-01204-w</link>
      <description>Walking Netball program successfully increased physical activity and improved physical function, mental health, and quality of life in middle-to-older age women, with 87.7% of groups sustaining participation beyond initial delivery through peer mentorship and tailored adaptation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3206251692</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity</source>
      <category>volleyball</category>
      <category>fan_engagement</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Elastic Band Exercises with PNF on Shooting Speed and Accuracy in Ball Hockey Players during the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph182111391</link>
      <description>Elastic band exercises with PNF maintained shooting speed and minimized accuracy deterioration in ball hockey players over 8 weeks during COVID-19 lockdown, compared to a control group that showed significant declines.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3208581750</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Support, Self-Regulation, and Psychological Skill Use in E-Athletes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.722030</link>
      <description>An international survey of 1,444 esports athletes found they reported significantly less social support, self-regulation, and psychological skill use than traditional athletes, and higher scores on these measures were associated with better in-game rank.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3209818008</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Frontiers in Psychology</source>
      <category>esports</category>
      <category>psychology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>041 Risk factors for dominant shoulder injury in elite female Australian cricket players: a prospective study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2021-ioc.39</link>
      <description>A prospective study of 115 elite female Australian cricketers identified shoulder internal-to-external rotation strength ratio as a significant predictor of dominant shoulder injury, with a 79% increased risk for every 0.1 ratio increase.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3214940931</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Living Sports Analytics</source>
      <category>cricket</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>042 Change of direction biomechanics and the risk for non-contact knee injuries in youth basketball and floorball players</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2021-ioc.40</link>
      <description>A prospective cohort study of 258 youth basketball and floorball players found female players had 6.2 times higher non-contact knee injury rates than males, with larger peak knee valgus angles, though biomechanical variables were not significantly associated with injury risk.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W3217656479</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Living Sports Analytics</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illness prevalence and symptoms in youth floorball players: a one-season prospective cohort study involving 471 players</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2021-051902</link>
      <description>A prospective cohort study of 471 youth floorball players over 26 weeks found 61% reported at least one illness week with 12% average weekly prevalence, higher in females, peaking in winter months (15-18%), with fever, sore throat, and cough as most common symptoms.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4200172054</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">BMJ Open</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>epidemiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacto de Dos Unidades Didácticas de Educación Deportiva sobre Objetivos de Aprendizaje en Educación Primaria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6018/cpd.462641</link>
      <description>Mixed-methods comparison of basketball and floorball education units in primary school found that sport type and student skill level significantly affected game performance and tactical knowledge acquisition, with floorball requiring more concrete instruction.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4205297310</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Cuadernos de Psicología del Deporte</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>player_development</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sports Injury and Illness Epidemiology: Thailand Team Surveillance During the 30th Southeast Asian Games</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5812/asjsm.116382</link>
      <description>Prospective surveillance of 980 Thai athletes at the 30th SEA Games found 86 injuries and 21 illnesses per 1000 athletes, with lower leg injury (14%) and ligament sprains (25%) most common, identifying priorities for injury prevention in multi-sport events.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4206063662</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Asian Journal of Sports Medicine</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>epidemiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study on Biomechanics of Two Legs in the Action of Single-Leg Landing in Men’s Badminton</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32604/mcb.2022.017044</link>
      <description>Motion capture analysis of single-leg landing in male badminton players revealed significant biomechanical differences between legs in center of gravity position, with implications for injury prevention.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4206180290</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Molecular &amp; cellular biomechanics</source>
      <category>badminton</category>
      <category>biomechanics</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utility of 2D Video Analysis for Assessing Frontal Plane Trunk and Pelvis Motion during Stepping, Landing, and Change in Direction Tasks: A Validity Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26603/001c.30994</link>
      <description>Concurrent validity study of 39 healthy participants found 2D video analysis appropriately correlated with 3D kinematics for assessing frontal plane trunk and pelvis motion during athletic landing tasks, though absolute agreement limits were wide.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4210814442</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy</source>
      <category>other</category>
      <category>methodology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Dual Task Interference on Biomechanics of the Entire Lower Extremity During the Drop Vertical Jump</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2478/hukin-2022-0001</link>
      <description>Kinematic analysis of 20 female collegiate athletes found concurrent cognitive task during drop vertical jump significantly increased peak external knee abduction moment and joint moments at hip and ankle with reduced knee flexion at initial contact.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4211097303</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Journal of Human Kinetics</source>
      <category>other</category>
      <category>biomechanics</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Análisis del clima motivacional en Educación Física a partir del empleo del modelo Teaching Games for Understanding (Analysis of the motivational climate in Physical Education from the use of the Teaching Games for Understanding model)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47197/retos.v44i0.92689</link>
      <description>Quasi-experimental study of 73 secondary students (39 experimental, 34 control) found that Teaching Games for Understanding pedagogy significantly improved perceived motivational climate in basketball units compared to traditional instruction.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4212976600</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Retos</source>
      <category>basketball</category>
      <category>player_development</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Learning Approach and Gender on Understanding, Fun, and Skills in Playing Soccer in Junior High School Students</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5614/jskk.2021.6.2.1</link>
      <description>An experimental factorial study with 60 junior high school students (30 boys, 30 girls) found that a tactical learning approach significantly improved understanding, enjoyment, and soccer playing skills, with differential effects by gender.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4213275793</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Jurnal Sains Keolahragaan dan Kesehatan</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>player_development</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening Tests for Assessing Athletes at Risk of ACL Injury or Reinjury—A Scoping Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19052864</link>
      <description>Scoping review identifies six categories of ACL injury screening tests (balance, gait, joint laxity, morphology, jump, strength) and recommends multitest approaches for injury risk assessment despite controversies in predictive validity.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4214506122</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validity of Velocity Measurements of a Motorized Resistance Device During Change of Direction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.824606</link>
      <description>Motorized resistance device velocity measurements during change of direction tasks show excellent validity (r=0.93-1.00) with low bias when compared to center of mass kinematics in male and female participants.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4214744226</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Frontiers in Physiology</source>
      <category>other</category>
      <category>biomechanics</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive trunk kinematics in healthy collegiate women&apos;s soccer players indicate trunk center of mass is laterally positioned prior to decelerating and cutting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jisako.2022.03.002</link>
      <description>Kinematic analysis of collegiate women&apos;s soccer players shows trunk center of mass is laterally positioned prior to deceleration and cutting maneuvers, relevant to ACL injury mechanisms.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4223905976</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Journal of ISAKOS Joint Disorders &amp; Orthopaedic Sports Medicine</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>biomechanics</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Warning of Basketball Injury Risk Based on Attribute Reduction Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/6981246</link>
      <description>Machine learning approach using attribute reduction algorithm for early warning of basketball injury risk aims to identify preventable training-related injury causes in college athletes.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4224113774</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Computational Intelligence and Neuroscience</source>
      <category>basketball</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cocreating injury prevention training for youth team handball: bridging theory and practice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjsem-2021-001263</link>
      <description>Participatory action research with youth handball coaches, players, and researchers co-creates evidence-based injury prevention training combining physical principles (technique, strength) and psychological aspects (motivation, body awareness).</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4225774518</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">BMJ Open Sport &amp; Exercise Medicine</source>
      <category>handball</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparing the Effects of Long-Term vs. Periodic Inclusion of Isometric Strength Training on Strength and Dynamic Performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000004276</link>
      <description>Twenty-four floorball athletes showed greater improvements in 5-m, 10-m, and 20-m sprint times with 24 consecutive weeks of isometric strength training compared to control, with no significant difference versus periodic inclusion.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4280511583</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">The Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Implementation of Athlete’s Knee Health Monitoring System Based on Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/4778376</link>
      <description>Cloud-based system using depth cameras and deep learning to monitor athlete knee joint health in real-time achieved 6% overall error rate and strong correlation with clinical KSS scoring.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4280633068</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Journal of Sensors</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organized Sport Activities of 11 to 15-Year-Old Adolescents: Trends from 2010–2018 and Socioeconomic Context</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19106074</link>
      <description>Czech adolescents from high-SES families were 3.01 times more likely to participate in organized individual sports than low-SES peers, with gaps widening with age from 2010–2018.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4280635401</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>player_development</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>International comparison of motor abilities and floorball skills in U-11 to U-14 teams from the Czech Republic and Australia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.34256/ijpefs2226</link>
      <description>Comparison of U-11 to U-14 floorball players from Czech Republic (n=18) and Australia (n=18) revealed statistically significant differences in all floorball skills but only one motor ability (Illinois agility test).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4282824326</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Physical Education Fitness and Sports</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>player_development</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of fitball aerobics on the development of individual coordinating abilities of girls 14–15 years old</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15391/snsv.2022-2.001</link>
      <description>Fitball aerobics intervention with 46 girls aged 14–15 significantly improved coordination abilities, with jump with turn increasing from 23.1% to 62.4% and Bondarevsky test from 18.6% to 30.6%.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4283034809</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Слобожанський науково-спортивний вісник</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Function of Perceived Corporate Social Responsibility in Safety of Sports Activities and Home Aerobic Equipment in the Late Period of COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2022.919254</link>
      <description>Structural equation modeling of 259 athletes revealed that perceived corporate social responsibility mediates the relationship between safety measures and injury prevention expectations, risk perception, and health outcomes in local sports bodies.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4283205223</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Frontiers in Psychology</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Game for Understanding (TGfU) Learning Design for Basketball Games in Physical Education</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.13189/saj.2022.100331</link>
      <description>Quasi-experimental study of 43 students showed Teaching Games for Understanding approach significantly improved decision-making (t=28.06 girls, t=18.56 boys), technical execution, game performance, and enjoyment in basketball.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4284694755</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International journal of human movement and sports sciences</source>
      <category>basketball</category>
      <category>coaching</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External focus facilitates cognitive stability and promotes motor performance of an interceptive task in children</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/1612197x.2022.2098356</link>
      <description>A study of 24 children performing a forehand drag shot in floorball found that external attentional focus improved task accuracy and reduced eye blinks compared to internal focus, suggesting external focus facilitates cognitive stability during interceptive tasks.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4284899860</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology</source>
      <category>floorball</category>
      <category>performance_analysis</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Peak Too Early: Evidence for an ACL Injury Prevention Mechanism of the 11+ Program</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26603/001c.36524</link>
      <description>A study of 69 collegiate female soccer players found that The 11+ intervention performed three times weekly reduced early-peak knee valgus moments during athletic tasks in one intervention team, suggesting a potential biomechanical mechanism for ACL injury prevention.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4289108993</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">International Journal of Sports Physical Therapy</source>
      <category>football</category>
      <category>injury_prevention</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiology and aetiology of sport‐related nasal fractures: Analysis of 599 Finnish patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/coa.13976</link>
      <description>Analysis of 599 Finnish patients with nasal fractures from 2013-2018 found that sports cause 15% of all nasal fractures, with highest prevalence in team sports (basketball, soccer, American football, rugby, baseball), martial arts, and equine sports, predominantly affecting young males.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://openalex.org/W4293199782</guid>
      <source url="https://living-sports-analytics.vercel.app">Clinical Otolaryngology</source>
      <category>multi_sport</category>
      <category>epidemiology</category>
      <category>journal_article</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
